杰森兰斯托夫: 查找网站，我们只是要步外纱工作区
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: The lookup site, we're
gonna just step outside of yarn workspaces
完全没有，只是没有压力。
entirely and just not stress about them.
所以我们要做的就是
So the way that this is gonna
work is we're going to start
只要进入网站，让它运行起来。
by just getting into the site and
getting it running.
所以让我们移动这个网站，如果我们看里面。
So let's get this site moving and
if we look inside.
这里面真的很少。
There's really very little in here.
我们添加了一些脚本，但是我们甚至还没有自己的依赖项。
We've got some scripts added, but
we don't even have our dependencies yet.
那么，让我们开始吧。
So let's, move into it.
我们要进入查找，然后我要纱加盖茨比反应-多姆。
We're gonna get into look up and then I'm
going to yarn add gatsby react react-dom.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的，我们看到了盖茨比的反应和表演。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, so we've got
gatsby react and react-dom in there.
现在我要做的是，我要设置两个页面。
And now what I wanna do is
I wanna set up two pages.
我想要一个索引页面，这将给我们提供我们的，就像我们的醒目页,
I want an index page and that's gonna give
us our, just kinda like our splash page,
它会链接到搜索页面。
it will link over to a search page.
而搜索页面就是这个应用实际上将要存在的地方。
And the search page is where
the app is actually gonna live.
那么让我们开始吧。
So let's go ahead and get those started.
因此，我们将从源文件夹、页面文件夹和 index.js 开始。
So we'll start with a source folder,
pages folder and index.js.
所以我要导入反应，从反应和这个特定的网站,
So I'm gonna import react from react and
for this particular site,
我们不用担心会不会弄得很漂亮。
we're not gonna worry
about making it look nice.
我们要跳过界面，我们要跳过一般的造型和
We're gonna skip the UI,
we're gonna skip styling in general and
只是把功能放在一起，因为我们今天花了很多时间在造型上
just put together the functionality cuz we
spent a lot of time on styling today and
我不想再重复同样的话题。
I don't want to re-hash the same ground.
所以让我们进口反应从反应,
So let's import react from react,
我们要从盖茨比那里进口林克。
we're going to import link from gatsby.
然后我们建立我们的索引页面。
And then we're gonna
set up our index page.
所以我们的索引页面会很简洁明了。
And so our index page is going
to be nice and straightforward.
我们将设置一个片段，这样就不会有任何额外的垃圾标记。
We will setup a fragment so
that we don't have any extra junky markup.
我们会说这将是瑞克和莫蒂的角色抬头看。
We'll say this is gonna be the Rick and
Morty character look up.
当我做这个的时候，我总觉得自己有点像个冒牌货。
I always feel like a little bit
of an impostor when I make this.
每次我和这个 Rick 一起工作
Whenever I work with this Rick and
因为我实际上只看过两集这个节目。
Morty API because I've actually only
ever seen two episodes of the show.
但是我喜欢这个 API，因为它非常适合演示和
But I love this API because
it's perfect for demos and
展示不同的事物是如何运作的。
showing off how different things work.
好吧，我们要说
Okay, so we're gonna say
我们来看看你最喜欢的
let's look up your favorite
从里克和
characters from Rick and
莫蒂利用瑞克和
Morty using the Rick and
网站: Rick and
Morty.API.com Rick and
Morty API.
好，然后在这里我们只是要链接到搜索页面
Okay and then down here we're just
gonna link to the search page which
我们需要创建，好吧，我认为这看起来像一页。
we'll need to create, okay and
I think that looks like a page.
所以让我们出口它。
So let's export it.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, and
然后我们创建-发言人2: 只是提醒一下,
then we'll create-
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Just a heads up,
你在2号线漏了一句话。
you're missing a single quote on line two.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 接得好。
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Good catch.
非常感谢。
Thank you very much.
现在它是自动格式化的。
There it goes now it's auto formatting.
太好了，谢谢。
Cool, thank you.
所以我们有了我们的索引，然后在我们的搜索，我实际上只是
So we've got our index and
then in our search I'm actually just
要采取大量的这一点，并投入正确的，我们会说。
gonna take a lot of this and
drop it right in and we'll say.
搜索 Rick & Morty 字符和
Search for Rick &amp; Morty characters and
然后我们可以说，给它一些有趣的市场复制品尝试
then we can say give it some
fun marketing copy trying
记住你说的是哪个 Rick？
to remember which,
Rick you're talking about?
试试这个方便的搜索界面，好吗。
Try out this handy search interface, okay.
所以在这里，我们可以设置
So in here, we're gonna be able to set up
一个真正的搜索界面但是现在,
an actual search interface but right now,
我们没有一个，所以我们需要添加一个搜索表格
we don't have one so
we need to add a search form and
我们需要增加结果，对吗？
we need to add results, right?
所以在这里，让我们做到这一点
So here, let's make it so
那种表情，我们知道我们希望我们的搜索结果在页面上显示。
that look, we know that we want our
search results to live on the page.
所以让我们继续向上移动这个。
So let's go ahead and move this up.
我打算用纱线显影。
And I'm just going to use yarn develop.
因为我们不再使用主题，所以我们不再需要使用工作区。
Because again, we're not using themes so
we don't need to use workspaces anymore.
我们可以直接进入并使用一个新的标准开发。
We can just jump right in and
use a new standard development.
所以这里是我们高度风格的 Rick & Morty API 查找，让我放大一点点。
So here is our highly styled Rick &amp; Morty
API lookup, let me zoom in a little bit.
当我点击我的搜索页面，我们可以看到我们的搜索页面。
And when I click over my search page,
we are able to see our search page.
所以我们现在要做的，就是在搜索表格中添加
And so what we have to do yet,
is we have to add in our search form, and
我们必须有结果。
we have to results.
但是根据搜索结果我们希望有人搜索,
But with the results, the way that we want
this to work is when somebody searches,
我们想让他们知道搜索的地点，比如说 Rick。
we wanted to show up where they're
going to search, let's say Rick.
这样就可以重定向到搜索页面并显示结果,
And that should redirect to the search
page and show us results, and that way,
如果我拿着这个复印一份然后发给别人,
if I take this, copy it,
and send it to somebody,
他们应该能看到结果。
they should be able to see those results.
你在搜索中遇到的一个主要问题是当你搜索到
One of the major problems that you
run into a search is when you have
我在搜索栏里输入它会显示搜索结果页面，但是
a search field, I type into it It
shows me the results page, but
网址上仍然只有搜索。
the URL still just says search.
所以我没有办法和别人分享这些结果。
So I have no way of sharing
those results with somebody.
所以如果我在电子商务网站上搜索
So if I'm looking for, like, if I'm on
an e-commerce site and I search for
这就是我想要的生日礼物
a product and I go,
this is what I want for my birthday, and
我想分享这个链接，嘿，你可以给我任何一个。
I want to share this link, hey,
you can give me any one of these.
我不能告诉别人，对吧？
I can't share that, right?
所以我拿不到生日礼物，大家都很伤心。
So I can't get my birthday present,
and everybody's sad.
所以我们想让我们的搜索结果可链接。
So we wanna make our
search results linkable.
为了做到这一点，您将利用《了不起的盖茨比》中的客户端路由。
And to do that, you will take advantage
of client-side routing in Gatsby.
幸运的是，有一个 API 可以实现这个功能。
Which fortunately,
there's an API for that.
所以在我们的根目录中，我们要创建一个 Gatsby node.js。
So in our root,
we're going to create a Gatsby node.js.
在我们的盖茨比节点中，我们将要寻找
And in our Gatsby node,
we are going to look for
创建页面 API。
the onCreatePage API.
因此，每当创建一个新页面时，创建页面就会触发
And so onCreatePage fires whenever
a new page gets created and
它允许我们在需要的时候修改它。
it allows us to modify it if we need to.
有很多事情你可以调整。
There are a bunch of
things that you can tweak.
具体来说，我们今天要做的就是寻找一条特定的道路。
Specifically, what we're going to do
today is look for a specific path.
如果我们找到了,
And if we find it,
我们要把它设置成动态的，就像客户端唯一的路线。
we're going to set it as a dynamic
like a client side only route.
那么我们来设定一下,
So let's set up if,
页面路径匹配，然后我们要使用我们的正则表达式。
the page path matches and then we're
gonna use our regular expression.
每个人都喜欢用这种方式让自己陷入麻烦。
Everybody's favorite way to
get themselves in trouble.
所以如果它以 / 搜索开始，我们知道我们在搜索页面上。
So if it starts with /search,
we know that we're on the search page.
所以如果我们回来了，我们知道我们在我们想要的地方。
So if that comes back through,
we know that we are where we wanna be.
然后我们要打电话给 matchpath 然后
So then,
we're gonna sat page.matchPath and
我们要把它设置成博客搜索。
we are just gonna set it
to search with the blog.
所以任何过去的事情
So anything that gets past this particular
Url / 搜索可能会被当作是同一个页面。
URL/search will kinda get treated
as if it's all the same page.
所有这些都会被重定向到搜索。
It will all get redirected to search.
然后，我们只需要调用 createPage 和 tweak 页面。
Then, we just call createPage
with the tweak page.
所以这只是覆盖了原创 createPage 的默认值。
So this just overrides the defaults
that were with the original createPage.
所以，这只是故事的一半，因为我们已经让盖茨比这么做了
So, this is only half of the story though
because we've told Gatsby to do it which
意味着盖茨比会尊重它但是如果我们刷新页面，如果我们得到链接
means that Gatsby will respect it But
if we refresh the page, if we get linked
从别的地方，我们永远不可能去盖茨比酒店，看到那些东西被渲染出来。
from somewhere else, we would never get
to the gatsby for that to get rendered.
所以接下来我们要做的就是设置一个重定向
So the next thing that we have to is
we have to set up a redirect and as
一个捷径，否定有一个真正方便的 CLI，它会让你做一堆事情。
a shortcut, nullify has a really handy CLI
that will let you do a bunch of things.
但最具体的是，它可以让您管理本地重定向。
But most specifically,
it'll let you manage redirects locally.
所以我要开始准备了。
So I'm gonna go ahead and set that up.
因此我们可以安装它与纱线全球添加 netlify-cli。
So we can install it with
yarn global add netlify-cli.
然后在我的路线上，我要创建一个文件叫做。
And then in my route,
I'm gonna create a file called.
我要创建一个叫 netlified.tamo 的文件
I'm gonna create a file
called netlified.tamo
塔莫就像动物一样更容易迷惑兄弟姐妹,
Tamo is like animals
more confusing sibling,
和它一起工作超级有趣，但我们就是这么用的。
and it's super fun to work with,
but this is how we use it.
所以你设置了重定向,
So [LAUGH] you set up redirects,
这是一个双数组，因为我想这意味着它像一个键，但
it's a double array because I guess
that means that it's Like a key but
可以有多个实例的关键，所以，双数组。
there can be multiple instances
of that key, so, double array.
然后我们设置从，它可以从任何搜索。
And then we setup from and
it can go from any search.
所以任何搜索实例,
So any instance of search,
它可以是 / search，然后是任意尾随字符数量。
it can be /search and
then any trailing amount of characters.
然后我们要重定向到搜索。
And then we're gonna
redirect that to search.
我们会发送一个状态码200,
And we're going to send
a status code of 200,
所以是重写而不是重定向。
which makes it a rewrite
instead of a redirect.
如果它是一个重定向，它将污染历史和
If it was a redirect,
it would pollute the history and
有各种各样的麻烦，我们不想卷入。
there's all sorts of trouble
that we don't want to get into.
所以我们只需要撒个弥天大谎。
So we're just gonna have netlify lie.
假设这个重定向从未发生，你只是得到了这个页面。
And say that that redirect never
happened and you just got the page.
这意味着我们现在可以打字了
So that means that we
should be able now to type
在斜线搜索之后的任何东西，它会把我们带到搜索结果页面。
anything after slash search and it should
bring us to that search results page.
为了测试它，我将使用 netlify dev。
To test it, I'm gonna use
something called netlify dev.
现在我们已经安装了网络化 CLI,
So now that we've
installed that netlify CLI,
我们有能力运行 netlify dev 来检测我们的 Gatsby 配置。
we have the ability to run netlify dev
which will detect our Gatsby config.
然后在8888端口启动，而不是8000,
And then it starts up on
port 8888 instead of 8000,
这是标准的 USB 端口，它将使我们的重定向工作，好吧。
which is the standard USB port, and
it will make our redirects work, okay.
因此，使开发人员网络化的方法是根据其在场程度自动识别盖茨比
So the way that netlify dev works is it
auto detects Gatsby based on the presence
档案。
of files.
为了让它认出这是盖茨比的遗址,
And so to trick it into
recognizing this as a Gatsby site,
我们要设置一个 Gatsby JS.config。
we're going to set up a Gatsby JS.config.
然后我们可以运行 netlify 开发，它将运行 gatsby 开发。
And then we can run netlify dev,
and it will run gatsby develop.
所以盖茨比配置不需要包含任何内容,
So the gatsby config doesn't
need to have anything in it,
只需要让 netlify dev 意识到这是一个盖茨比的地盘。
it just needs to exist for netlify dev
to recognize that it's a gatsby site.
现在在任何一个真正的网站上，你都会有一些盖茨比式的配置。
Now in any real site, you're gonna
have some kind of gatsby config.
你将有网站元数据的搜索引擎优化。
You'll have site metadata for the SEO.
你会得到类似的东西。
You'll have things like that.
所以这并不是一件不合理的事情。
So that's not an unreasonable
thing to expect to exist.
那么现在我们已经可以看到我们的搜索,
So now,
we can already see that our search,
我可以把任何东西放在这里，但它还是会把我们带回到那个搜索页面。
I can put anything in here, and it's still
gonna take us back to that search page.
如果我回来直接进行搜索，它仍然会显示搜索页面。
And if I come back and just go to straight
search, it still shows us the search page.
所以在这一点上，我们得到的是一个功能性的客户端应用程序
So at this point, what we've got is a
functioning client side app that will take
不管我们在搜索页面上放了什么，一定要把我们带到搜索部分。
whatever we throw at that search page, and
always bring us to that search component.
这样我们就可以实际执行查找部分了。
And that sets us up to actually
do the the lookup part.
因此，让我们保存我们的工作和
So let's save our work and
然后我们再加上下一段。
then we'll add to that next piece.